Whatever.
算了
I'll move it myself.
我自己来移
That suit...
那套战斗服…
Wh-Who are you?
你到底是谁？
Examinee number 2016.
准考证号码2016号
Kikoru Shinomiya.
四之宫琪歌露
My hobby is murdering Kaiju.
兴趣是扑杀怪兽
Remember that.
你们给我记好了
Shinomiya?
四之宫？
Old man...
大叔
Did you know you smell like a Kaiju?
你好像散发着怪兽的味道耶？
W-We work in Kaiju disposal!
我们的工作是处理怪兽尸体
What's a pair of disposal workers doing here?
清洁业者在这里做什么？
Up you go...
嘿咻
Don't tell me he's got his own private suit too!
莫非那家伙也穿了私人战斗服？
Examinee number 2032. Kafka Hibino.
准考证号码2032号，日比野卡夫卡
Remember the name, kiddo.
你给我记好了，小妹
And he took my parking space while we were talking!
结果我的车位就这样被抢走了
Stupid helpful butler!
臭管家真精明！
I was expecting the exam to be a formality,
我本来以为这场测验只是个必经阶段
but this might actually be kind of fun.
看来似乎还有点乐趣嘛
I'm gonna show you up bad, Kafka Hibino.
看我怎么让你哭丧着脸，日比野卡夫卡
Let's go, Sebasu.
濑羽须，我们走
Of course.
是！
Didn't take you long to use your powers.
你立刻就使出力量了嘛
But wasn't it cool how I only transformed the part she couldn't see?
不过，我有好好控制 只有别人看不到的部位变身
That's not the issue!
问题不在这里
Hey, we heard a loud noise.
我们听到很大的声响，是有什么问题吗？
No, nothing! Everything's fine here!
不，没什么事，没问题
Then get going.
那就快点进去吧
Okay!
知道了
Next time you pull that stunt, I'm sending you home.
要是再有下次，我就把你强制遣返
Okay...
好的
I gave up on this once...
虽然我曾经一度放弃
But this is my last chance to stand beside her!
但这是我和她并肩而立的最后机会
This time, I ain't giving up!
这次，我绝对不会放弃
EPISODE 3: REVENGE MATCH
（第3集：雪耻之战）
Huh? What the hell is this?
奇怪，这是怎么回事？
I can't keep up at all!
我完全跟不上
I'd been keeping up my training out of habit!
我明明有维持锻炼的习惯
And I do really hard physical work every day!
而且每天都进行体力劳动工作
The second round has two parts, a fitness test and an aptitude test.
第二阶段测验分成 体力审查与适性审查这两个部分
Yeah.
没错
The aptitude test is something you've either got or you don't.
适性审查是看资质，这方面我们无从掌控
Which means...
这样一来…
Yeah.
嗯
We want to get the best grades we can in the fitness test.
我们要在体力审查取得高分
Before, I used to be just below average!
之前我好歹也有达到中下程度吧
But now...
可是现在…
Do you really get this weak when you turn thirty?
这就是三十岁以后的衰退现象吗？
If I used my power,
如果我使出力量
I wonder if I could get to the front of the pack.
有办法一口气超越所有人吗？
Damn it...
可恶
My body doesn't want to move at all!
身体好沉重
KAFKA HIBINO FITNESS TEST RANK:
（日比野卡夫卡，体力审查结果）
219 OUT OF 225
（225人中第219名）
KAFKA HIBINO
（日比野卡夫卡）
KIKORU SHINOMIYA
（四之宫琪歌露，225人中第5名）
Well, it didn't take long to show you up.
你这么快就哭丧着脸了啊
Kafka Hibino.
日比野卡夫卡
Remember the name, kiddo.
你给我记好了，小妹
Kiddo!
小妹…
Forget it! Forget my name right now!
快忘掉！你快忘掉我的名字吧
I feel so much better.
我放心了
You really didn't use your Kaiju power, did you?
你真的没有使用怪兽的力量呢
Everybody's put in a lot of effort to get here.
每个来这里的人都很努力
It wouldn't be fair to use my power.
如果只有我靠着怪兽的力量过关 那就太卑鄙了吧
I thought it would be so cool to say that, but I should've used it!
我耍什么帅啊？我应该要用的啊
It's been ages since I last tried this test!
空窗期很不妙啊
I don't think that's the only reason you got the ranking you did.
前辈的名次会落后，也许不只那个原因
Here are the applicants this year.
这是这次的考生
A lot look pretty interesting.
似乎有不少有趣的家伙
Not that you care about anything but killing Kaiju, I'm sure.
不过，你应该只对打倒怪兽有兴趣吧
Continue.
你继续说
I'll listen while I work.
我边工作边听
Oh, that's rare.
哦？真稀奇啊
The first person I've got my eye on is...
那从值得瞩目的人说起，首先是…
Haruichi Izumo.
出云阳一
Yeah. That's a good idea.
确实不错…
Graduated top of his class from Tokyo Neutralization University.
东京讨伐大学第一名毕业
HARUICHI IZUMO FITNESS TEST RANK: 2ND
（出云阳一，体力审查第2名）
Then there's Iharu Furuhashi,
接着是古桥伊春
a powerhouse valedictorian at Hachioji Neutralization Technical College.
八王子讨伐专科学校第一名毕业的强者
Yes!
好耶
Aoi Kaguragi, the rising star of the Japan Ground Self-Defense Force.
陆上自卫队的年轻新星，神乐木葵
AOI KAGURAGI FITNESS TEST RANK: 1ST
（神乐木葵，体力审查第1名）
He turned down a sure spot in the JGSDF elite to come to the Defense Force.
他舍弃了在陆上自卫队的大好前途 转而申请加入防卫队
And that's not all.
而且不只他们
There're more applicants
来自各地的讨伐大学
from neutralization universities and colleges than most years.
以及专科学校的人也比往年还多
Normally, these people would be trying to become elite officers,
他们本来应该不是跑现场的角色
not field agents.
而是要当储备干部的菁英
No wonder they all seemed so damn good...
难怪大家的程度都那么好
And the big one everybody's watching is her.
然后其中最特别的，就是她了
Graduated from California Neutralization at age 16.
16岁就从加利福尼亚讨伐大学
She skipped grades and became the youngest ever to do so.
跳级毕业的最年轻的第一名毕业生
They call her the greatest talent ever.
被誉为史上最优秀的天才少女
Kikoru Shinomiya.
四之宫琪歌露
I'm gonna kick her ass.
看我怎么打倒她
Now, let's see if I've got any hope against her.
让我想想，我该怎么对付她呢？
Let's see what you've got.
我就来看看她的能耐
It's a group of extremely skilled applicants,
以四之宫琪歌露为首
none more so than Kikoru Shinomiya.
出类拔萃的成员齐聚一堂
So you...
所以前辈你才…
So she's...
她…
Oh?
唉呀
Did you finally figure out how awesome I am, Kafka Hibino?
你总算知道我有多伟大了吗？ 日比野卡夫卡
I had no idea you were so amazing!
原来你这么厉害啊
Don't touch the mistress!
不准碰我家小姐
Who the hell is that guy?
那个大叔是怎样啊？
Some groupie of Shinomiya's?
他是四之宫的追随者吗？
Second time you got shown up today, Kafka Hibino.
这是你第二次哭丧着脸了，日比野卡夫卡
Let's see how many more times that'll happen today.
我还要再让你哭几次呢？
Well, I'm gonna show you up too!
我也会让你哭丧着脸的！
I'm just about screwed, though.
话虽如此，我已经身陷绝境了
There's still hope.
还有希望
For the last two years, the second part of today's test
最近这两年，下一项适性审查中
has been Kaiju corpse disposal.
有出现处理怪兽尸体的题目
What?
什么？
They want to test knowledge of Kaiju,
他们把对于怪兽的知识
as well as your ability to work in a group.
以及沟通协调能力列入考量
And also make sure applicants realize that
要让大家知道 讨伐怪兽不仅是打倒怪兽而已
there's more to the job than just killing Kaiju.
似乎兴起了这种意识改革
That's why I chose to work in disposal for my part-time job.
这也是我选择到解体产业打工的理由
Okay!
好
Let's bet it all on the next part!
-我们把希望放在下一关吧 -嗯
DEFENSE FORCE TRAINING AREA TWO
（防卫队第二演习场）
It's huge.
好大啊
I'm Third Division Vice-Captain Hoshina.
我是这次第二阶段测验的审查委员长
You'll be doing your aptitude test here in this area.
适性审查就在这个演习场进行
Your task in this area will be to find Kaiju and...
大家就在要这个演习场把怪兽…
Dispose of their bodies!
解体！
...neutralize them!
…讨伐
Neutralize them?
-讨… -伐？
What happened to disposing of their bodies, Ichikawa-san?
说好的解体呢？市川先生！
I just said that's what it was for the past two years!
我只是说前两年是这样
I'm disappointed too!
我也觉得很遗憾啊
But we can't send you in empty-handed,
不过总不能让大家赤手空拳上阵 所以要请你们…
so you'll be wearing these.
穿上这个
So this is Izumo Tech gear, huh?
这是出云科技制造的…
The G-X4552, huh?
G-X4552啊？
What is this?
怎么回事？
Wow...
好厉害
It's pressing itself up against my body...
感觉衣服好像吸住了身体
Body measurements and form assimilation complete.
身体测量及身形同化完成
Kaiju muscle fibers, fully operational.
怪兽肌肉纤维，运作正常
It's becoming one with my body.
开始跟我的身体合而为一了
I can feel my muscles getting stronger!
我感受得到肌肉在膨胀
It's hot...
好热
So this is...
这就是…
This is a Defense Force Kaiju combat suit.
防卫队的怪兽对策战斗服
It's made from organic material taken from Kaiju,
由怪兽的生物组织制成
and massively multiplies the combat power of its wearer.
穿上之后战斗力会大幅提升
For now, there's no better weapon you have against the Kaiju.
对目前的各位来说 这是对抗怪兽最有效的装备
Measuring the unleashed combat power of the ones who have their suits on.
现在从着装完毕的人开始测量解放战力
Understood.
了解
Reno Ichikawa. Unleashed combat power, 8%.
市川雷诺，解放战力8%
Haruichi Izumo, 18%.
出云阳一，18%
Sounds about right, I guess.
差不多这样吧
Aoi Kaguragi, 15%.
神乐木葵，15%
Understood.
是
Iharu Furuhashi, 14%.
古桥伊春，14%
What?
什么？
Unleashed combat power indicates
解放战力
how much of the suit's power you've drawn out.
是判定能发挥多少战斗服力量的指标
Even after training, it's usually around 20%.
受过训练的话，通常约为20%
We're lucky to get one applicant a year above 10%.
超过10%的人，每年有一个就算好的了
This year might be a bumper crop like we've never seen before.
今年说不定真的会成为 有史以来最丰收的一年呢
Seriously?
不会吧？
Kikoru Shinomiya...
四之宫琪歌露
Unleashed combat power,
解放战力…
46%!
46%
She's already at the level of a platoon leader.
这不是已经跟小队长同等级了吗？
The greatest talent in history...
史上最优秀的天才
This has to be a record for anybody who hasn't officially joined yet.
这是入队前的最高纪录了吧？
Just 8%...
我只有8%
Oh, there's no reason to get down, Ichikawa-kun.
市川，你不必沮丧
If you get an 8% on your first time, you did well.
第一次能有8%也算不错了
Honestly, if you don't have a zero at this point, you pass.
老实说，现阶段只要不是0%都可以合格
And I've never even seen a zero!
我还没看过有人是0%的
Kafka Hibino...
日比野卡夫卡
Unleashed combat power,
解放战力…
0%!
0%
What's wrong with him?
这家伙是怎样？
Wow, he's my first zero!
0%出现了耶
Huh? Are the measurements wrong?
奇怪，是不是测量失误啊？
Just give me a little more time!
再给我一点时间
I'm trying to squeeze it out!
我正在用力
You're not trying to take a dump!
这又不是在拉屎
You can't squeeze it out!
你用力也没用啊
Wow, the old guy is hilarious!
这个大叔超幽默的耶
I like him!
我喜欢
He probably won't pass, though.
不过他大概没办法合格吧
Take your proctoring job seriously!
请你认真审查
Why?
为什么？
Damn it! There's got to be some trick!
可恶，这应该有什么诀窍
I need to figure it out before the exam ends!
我得赶在测验结束前找出来
You're pissing me off, Kafka Hibino.
日比野卡夫卡，真是令人焦躁
Show the power I saw in the parking lot already!
快点展现你在停车场的那股力量啊
The exam's almost over!
测验都快结束了
Okay, now that you're all in your suits...
好，既然大家都着装完毕了
Let's start the final test.
最终审查，就要开始咯
DEFENSE FORCE SCREENING EXAM FINAL TEST
（防卫队员选拔测验，最终审查）
I'll explain the test.
现在说明测验内容
Your targets are a Honju and 36 Yoju
目标是在广阔的
that have been placed throughout the urban training area.
市街型演习场里配置的主兽和36只余兽
These Kaiju caused sixteen fatalities in Hachioji last year.
这些怪兽去年在八王子造成16人遇害
We captured them alive to serve as training aids.
被我们活捉来用于培训新进队员
You're going to fight them with anti-Kaiju weapons.
就请各位使用对付怪兽的武器作战
You'll all be tracked with a drone that will monitor your actions.
每个人都会有一台自动追踪无人机 观察各位的行动
If we decide your life is in danger,
如果经我们判断有危及生命的情况
we'll remotely activate the shield on your suit,
就会远端启动战斗服的防护盾
but be aware this will mean you fail.
但这也就代表会当场失去资格
To be honest, I can't guarantee you'll survive this next part.
坦白说，接下来我们无法保证生命安全
go.
就向前冲吧
What the hell?
那是怎样啊？
Yoju 12 down.
已消灭余兽12号
Yoju 03 down.
已消灭余兽03号
Wow...
好厉害
Damn it! Let's get going too!
可恶，我们也走吧
Don't fall behind, Ichikawa!
市川，你好好跟上
That's my line!
那是我的台词吧
This equipment is incredibly heavy without the suit helping you!
没有战斗服辅助，这个装备实在有够重
Only I, the zero, can understand this!
这点只有0%的我才懂
Don't make it sound cool!
你别说得好像自己很帅气
But what do we do?
不过，我们该怎么办？
We don't have that kind of offensive power.
我们又没有那么强的攻击力
Oh, I forgot.
对了，有件事我忘了说
Captain Mina Ashiro is here for the test as well.
亚白米娜队长也会参与适性审查
Do your best to look good for her.
大家可要好好表现哦
Let's see who can be a cooler Defense Force officer!
我们来比赛，看谁能成为帅气的防卫队员
That's right...
对啊
Who cares if I'm a zero?
0%又怎样？
Calm down. This is your last chance.
我得冷静，这是最后的机会了
Ichikawa.
市川
Why are the examining officers following us all with drones?
审查官使用无人机 跟着每个人的理由是什么？
True... If all they cared about was how many Kaiju you killed,
确实，审核基准如果只看讨伐数量
they could just track that number with sensors.
应该只要用感应器计算就好了
Yup.
没错
They're testing our abilities,
他们是想看考生会如何
but also how we can adapt to the situation.
根据能力与状况进行应对
Which means since we lack that kind of offensive capability, we should...
这样的话，攻击力不高的我们 该采取的行动就是…
Yup!
没错
Support all the attackers as best we can!
我们要尽全力支援攻击手
Right!
好
Damn it!
可恶
Senpai! Engagement to our right!
前辈，右方交战中
Okay! Go around from the side and provide support!
好，我们绕过去援护
Those hooves...
这个蹄的形状…
I know this guy!
我知道这种怪兽
The one we did a joint disposal of with Iida Cleaners!
是我们跟饭田解体一起处理的余兽
So that's why they included these in our equipment...
原来如此，所以装备里才会有这个东西啊
Eat this!
接招吧！
A stun grenade?
震撼手榴弹？
It's got weak eyesight but incredibly good hearing!
这家伙因为眼睛退化，所以听觉很发达
Once you've deafened them, they're easy targets!
只要让它听觉受影响，事情就好办了
The stomach!
腹部！
The skin on its stomach is weaker than most Kaiju!
跟其他怪兽比起来 这家伙的腹部皮肤比较薄
Aim for the stomach!
瞄准腹部
What?
什么？
Thanks for the support, Shinomiya groupie!
感谢你的助攻，四之宫的追随者
I am not a groupie!
我才不是她的追随者
We did it, Senpai!
前辈，干得好
Yeah, we've taken apart more Kaiju bodies than we can count!
毕竟我可是处理过数不清的怪兽
We know you guys inside and out!
对于怪兽，我可是连内脏都了若指掌
I can do this!
我可以的
I don't have to use my Kaiju power!
就算不靠怪兽的力量也办得到
I'll make up for all my screw-ups!
我要让至今搞砸的都一笔勾销
I'll throw the next one!
下一次让我来投掷吧
Let's keep it up!
就照这样继续…
Another one?
还有另一只？
Senpai!
前辈！
Area Delta, Number 2032 injured.
戴尔塔区，2032号考生受伤
Irregularities detected in vitals. He's unable to continue combat.
生命征象出现异常，无法战斗
Yoju 23 is continuing to approach.
余兽23号正在继续追击
Prepare the remote shield.
准备远端保护盾
Ow...
好痛
Crap.
糟糕
They're gonna put the shield up...
他们要启动远端防护盾了
...but be aware this will mean you fail.
…就代表会当场失去资格
Stand up...
我得站起来
She's...
她…
She's watching!
她正在看着啊
I can't embarrass myself in front of her anymore!
我不能再在她面前丢人现眼了
Activating remote shield!
启动远端防护盾
Figured he'd be the first to drop out.
第一个淘汰者果然是他啊
He was a funny guy... Too bad.
虽然他很有趣，但也无可奈何
That's the third time, Kafka Hibino.
这是你第三次哭丧着脸咯，日比野卡夫卡
When I'm on the battlefield, nobody gets to quit.
在我的战场上，我不允许有人弃权
Kikoru! You saved me!
琪歌露，你救了…
I'll go defeat the rest of them,
我会把怪兽收拾地一干二净
so you just lie on the ground like a loser.
你就继续惨兮兮地躺着吧
She's going after the main target?
她打算去对付主兽吗？
I'll take it out first!
休想抢先我
Better pay attention!
不可以东张西望
She's so much more powerful!
威力也太强大了吧
Is that really the same equipment we've got?
我们的装备真的一样吗？
So your unleashed combat power makes that much of a difference, huh?
解放战力的差异 竟然会让威力有这么大的不同
Damn it... I'll go too!
可恶，我也…
Senpai!
前辈！
It's broken?
骨折了吗？
I can't stand up!
这样我站不起来
2032, can you hear me?
2032号，你听得见吗？
This is Hoshina in the operation room.
我是作战室的保科
We're seeing irregularities in your vitals.
你的生命征象出现异常
Multiple fractures, probably.
应该是身上有多处骨折
Possibly organ damage.
搞不好内脏也受到损伤了
No...
怎么这样…
Do I have to give up?
我只能放弃了吗？
No... while there's still a chance, I'll…
不，只要还有可能，我就…
I'll never be able to stand by her side...
想跟她并肩而立，已经不可能了…
It's always the ones with talent who pass.
每次被录取的总是有天分的人
As the test proctor, I recommend you drop out.
以审查官的立场，我建议你弃权
Even those shields aren't perfect.
防护盾并无法百分之百保障安全
I'm the one who decides
能决定要不要放弃的
if I give up or not.
只有我自己
Senpai.
前辈
I'm too old for dreams...
年纪不小了还在追梦
I know I look like an idiot, but...
我也知道自己这样很不堪
I've decided to bet my whole life up to this point
但我已经决定赌上整个人生
and chase my dreams again!
再度追逐梦想
This time...
这次…
This time, I'm not giving up, no matter what!
这次我绝对不会放弃！